<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>uMUSCLE on UGENE Documentation</title><link>https://ugene.net/docs/extensions/umuscle/</link><description>Recent content in uMUSCLE on UGENE Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ugene.net/docs/extensions/umuscle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MUSCLE Aligning</title><link>https://ugene.net/docs/extensions/umuscle/muscle-aligning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ugene.net/docs/extensions/umuscle/muscle-aligning/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="muscle-aligning">MUSCLE Aligning&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>To run the classic MUSCLE use the &lt;em>Align ‣ Align with MUSCLE&lt;/em> context menu item in the &lt;em>Alignment Editor&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ugene.net/docs/images/65930833/65930834.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dialog contains the list of MUSCLE modes: &lt;em>MUSCLE default&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Large alignment&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Refine only&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ugene.net/docs/images/65930833/65930835.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default UGENE does not rearrange sequence order in an alignment, but the original MUSCLE package does. To enable sequence rearrangement uncheck the &lt;em>Do not re-arrange sequences (-stable)&lt;/em> option in the dialog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the improvements to the original MUSCLE package is the ability to align only a part of the model. When the &lt;em>Column range&lt;/em> item is selected the region of the specified columns is only passed to the MUSCLE alignment engine. The resulted alignment is inserted into the original one with gaps added or removed on the region boundaries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aligning Profile to Profile with MUSCLE</title><link>https://ugene.net/docs/extensions/umuscle/aligning-profile-to-profile-with-muscle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ugene.net/docs/extensions/umuscle/aligning-profile-to-profile-with-muscle/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="aligning-profile-to-profile-with-muscle">Aligning Profile to Profile with MUSCLE&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Align ‣ Align profile to profile with MUSCLE&lt;/em> context menu item allows to align an existing profile to an active alignment. During this process the MUSCLE does not realign the profiles, but inserts columns with gaps characters only (‘—’ characters). For example, the alignment in the picture below could be used as a profile:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ugene.net/docs/images/65930836/65930837.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The same profile after profile-to-profile alignment:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ugene.net/docs/images/65930836/65930838.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two gap columns inserted into the source profile, and two gap columns inserted into the added one. Therefore the profiles columns kept intact and the alignments haven’t been changed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aligning Sequences to Profile with MUSCLE</title><link>https://ugene.net/docs/extensions/umuscle/aligning-sequences-to-profile-with-muscle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ugene.net/docs/extensions/umuscle/aligning-sequences-to-profile-with-muscle/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="aligning-sequences-to-profile-with-muscle">Aligning Sequences to Profile with MUSCLE&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Another feature provided by the plugin is aligning a set of unaligned sequences to an existing profile. To use this feature select the &lt;em>Align ‣ Align sequences to profile with MUSCLE&lt;/em> context menu item.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This option is not available in the original MUSCLE package (v3.7) and is a new functionality for original MUSCLE users. In this mode each sequence from the input file is aligned to the active profile separately and is merged to the result alignment only after all sequences are processed. For example, the alignment in the picture above can be used as a profile again. And the added profile can be used as a set of sequences. The result of such sequences-to-profile alignment is presented on the picture below:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>